<?xml version="1.0" encoding="euc-jp"?>

<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" "../dtd/docbook/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd">

<!-- ********************************************************************
$Id$
******************************************************************** -->

<article id="index">
    <title>Java Service Wrapper Release Notes</title>
    <section id="3.1.1">
        <title>Version 3.1.1: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modified the way libwrapper.so is built on Solaris and Linux so that it
                    no longer statically links its required libraries.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a file handle leak when calling WrapperManager.getUser or
                    WrapperManager.getInteractiveUser on Windows platforms.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem introduced in 3.1.0 where the JVM would not be restarted
                    correctly if it quit after a ping timeout to let the Wrapper resynch and
                    restart it.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where CTRL-C was not being handled correctly if the console
                    was configured to be shown when running as an NT service.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where signals fired at UNIX versions of the wrapper were
                    not being handled correctly when the tick timer was being used.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a synchronization problem in the logging code which would
                    occassionally cause the Wrapper to crash with an Access Violation.
                    The problem was only encountered when the tick timer was enabled,
                    and was only seen on multi-CPU systems.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?func=detail&amp;aid=949877&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425187">Bug #949877</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Increase debug output on UNIX platforms when a signal is caught.  When
                    possible, information about where the signal came from is now logged.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem when using the tick timer where the Wrapper would sometimes
                    exit on startup due to an uncaught SIGALRM.  Only reported on multi-CPU
                    Solaris systems.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the Wrapper would sometimes hang on shutdown if
                    another thread called System.exit while the Wrapper was shutting down.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?func=detail&amp;aid=955248&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425187">Bug #955248</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem introduced in 3.1.0 where a very very large CPU timeout
                    warning message was being displayed if the system time was set back
                    while using the default system timer.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new property, <ulink url="prop-anchorfile.html">wrapper.anchorfile</ulink>,
                    which makes it possible to cause the Wrapper to shutdown by deleting
                    an anchor file.  The UNIX sh script has been modified to optionally make
                    use of this feature.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add a debug message at startup which makes it clear which timer is being
                    used.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    A Windows user reported that using forward slashes in the path the log
                    file was failing.  Avoid this problem by always converting '/' to '\'
                    in the <ulink url="prop-logfile.html">wrapper.logfile</ulink> property
                    on Windows.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where is was not possible disable the wrapper log file as
                    documented in the <ulink url="prop-logfile.html">wrapper.logfile</ulink>
                    property.  Most likely broken way back in version 2.2.5.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add some additional error checks after calls to control the pipe between
                    the JVM and Wrapper as well as improving the messages around other socket
                    related error messages.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="3.1.0">
        <title>Version 3.1.0: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The <ulink url="license.html">license</ulink> was revised for this version
                    to include a copyright omission.  This change is to be retroactively applied
                    to all versions of the Java Service Wrapper starting with version 3.0.0.
                    The changes should have no effect on users.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The Online documentation and web site were both reworked.  The logo has
                    been updated so that Duke is no longer used.  The new online
                    <ulink url="http://wrapper.tanukisoftware.org">site</ulink> now
                    has the ability for users to append comments to any page.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new batch file which accepts commands like the UNIX shell script.
                    The new file is offered as an alternative to the default batch files, and
                    can be found at <literal moreinfo="none">src/bin/AppCommand.bat.in</literal>.
                    Thanks to Mike Castle for donating the new script.  See the new
                    <ulink url="launch-win.html#command">Command-Based Script</ulink>
                    section for more information.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The Windows version of the Wrapper was not correctly registering that it
                    would accept SHUTDOWN messages when running as a service.  The Wrapper
                    was getting the message anyway so this should not change functionality.
                    Thanks to Jason Tishler for noticing this and sending in a patch.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add a new property, <ulink url="prop-native-library.html">wrapper.native_library</ulink>,
                    which can be used to specify the base name of the native library which is
                    loaded by the WrapperManager class.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modify the WrapperManager class so it now stores references to System.out
                    and System.err on initialization and always writes to those stored streams.
                    This makes sure that all Wrapper console output always goes to the
                    wrapper.log file even if user code overrides those streams with calls to
                    System.setOut and System.setErr.  This was necessary to prevent deadlocks
                    in such user code from affecting the functionality of the Wrapper.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fixed a problem where some environment variables where not being correctly
                    loaded from the system registry when running as an NT service.  Big thanks
                    to Eric Smith for tracking this down and submitting a patch.  It turns out
                    that the putenv function was not being used correctly.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modified the way the wrapper.conf file is loaded so it will now read the
                    contents correctly even if the line feeds in the file are incorrect for
                    the current platform.  Windows line feeds had been causing problems when
                    used on UNIX platforms.  
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=829896&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425190">Feature Request #829896</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new property, <ulink url="prop-ntservice-console.html">wrapper.ntservice.console</ulink>,
                    which allows a console to be displayed when running as an NT service.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fixed a problem where the <ulink url="prop-request-thread-dump-on-failed-jvm-exit.html">request thread dump on failed JVM exit</ulink>
                    feature had never worked when running as an NT service.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=831775&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425187">Bug #831775</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add a new property, <ulink url="prop-console-title.html">wrapper.console.title</ulink>,
                    which makes it possible to set the title of the console in which the Wrapper
                    is currently running.  This currently only works on Windows platforms.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new method, setConsoleTitle, to the
                    <ulink url="javadocs.html">WrapperManager</ulink> class which
                    enables the application to dynamically set the console title.  Like the
                    <ulink url="prop-console-title.html">wrapper.console.title</ulink>
                    property, this only works on Windows platforms.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Improved the algorithm of the <ulink url="prop-request-thread-dump-on-failed-jvm-exit.html">request thread dump on failed JVM exit</ulink>
                    feature so that extremely large thread dumps will not be truncated when
                    the JVM is killed.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where CTRL-C was being ignored by the WrapperManager if a
                    WrapperListener is never registered.  This is not possible if the Wrapper
                    is being used correctly but never the less a user did come across it.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add some additional debug output to help identify the cause of problems
                    loading the native library.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The WrapperManager class now checks to make sure that its current version
                    matches the version of the native library and Wrapper.  If there are any
                    discrepancies found then appropriate warnings will be displayed, but the
                    Application will still be allowed to start.  This was added to make obvious
                    the cause of problems resulting from mismatched versions.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new property <ulink url="prop-use-system-time.html">wrapper.use_system_time</ulink> system time.  By setting this
                    property to false, the Wrapper will start using a new experimental timer
                    which uses a background thread to manage time rather than the system time.
                    This has a number of advantages over using the system time and should give
                    most users even more reliable behavior when the system is under high load
                    or there are changes being made to the system time.  The timer is very
                    critical to the operation of the Wrapper so the old behavior is left as
                    the default for the time being until this feature has had the chance to be
                    "time" tested.  If all goes well then this will be enabled as the default
                    in a future version of the Wrapper.
                    A pair of related properties, <ulink url="prop-use-system-time.html#prop-timer-fast-threshold">wrapper.timer_fast_threshold</ulink> and
                    <ulink url="prop-use-system-time.html#prop-timer-slow-threshold">wrapper.timer_slow_threshold</ulink>
                    were also added to aid in debugging.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Rework the logging code so it is now thread safe.  The addition of the
                    timer thread means that there is now more than a single thread accessing
                    that code.  This was causing problems as the two threads tried to use the
                    same buffers.  As part of this change, a new format variable 'D' was added
                    to display the thread which is doing the logging.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where a thread dump would be invoked if the
                    <ulink url="prop-request-thread-dump-on-failed-jvm-exit.html">request thread dump on failed JVM exit</ulink>
                    was enabled and the user forced an immediate shutdown by pressing CTRL-C
                    more than once.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add getUser and getInteractiveUser methods to the <ulink url="javadocs.html">WrapperManager</ulink>
                    class to make it possible for user code to query information about the user
                    running Wrapper or the user who is interacting with the Wrapper and its JVM.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=812175&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425190">Feature Request #812175</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The Wrapper will now always exit with the exit code used to terminate the JVM
                    whether System.exit is used or <ulink url="javadocs.html">WrapperManager.stop</ulink>.
                    When running as an NT service the Wrapper now correctly returns the correct
                    exit code to the service manager so failure recovery tools should now work
                    correctly.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=852491&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425190">Feature Request #852491</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add a status command to the UNIX shell script which can be used to find out
                    whether or not the wrapper is currently running.  Patch submitted by
                    Joseph Benavidez.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modify the WrapperSimpleApp and WrapperStartStopApp so that the main method
                    of a class is located even if it exists in a parent class rather than the
                    class specified.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    To make debugging classpath problems easier, the Wrapper now verifies all
                    classpath entries before launching a JVM and logs debug level warnings for
                    any entries that do not exist.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where it was possible to define a zero length filter that would
                    trigger on any output.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add some additional debug output to make it easier to debug startup,
                    shutdown and restart problems.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modify the way the Wrapper forcibly kills a frozen JVM on UNIX platforms so
                    that it now sends a SIGTERM, waits up to 5 seconds, then sends a SIGKILL.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add a new <ulink url="prop-java-library-path-append-system-path.html">wrapper.java.library.path.append_system_path</ulink>
                    which will cause the Wrapper to append the system path to the generated
                    library path.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=917902&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425190">Feature Request #917902</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where spaces around the '=' character of a property definition
                    were rendering the property invisible to the Wrapper.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=916001&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425187">Bug #916001</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the first ping timeout after the JVM was started was
                    still hard coded at 30 seconds.  This was causing a combination of large
                    values of <ulink url="prop-ping-interval.html">wrapper.ping.interval</ulink>
                    and <ulink url="prop-ping-timeout.html">wrapper.ping.timeout</ulink> to fail.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the JVM would fail to shutdown cleanly if the Wrapper
                    was asked to stop too soon after launching a JVM.  This was leading to the
                    JVM being killed after the shutdown timeout expired.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=917281&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425187">Bug #917281</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added an adviser which will print out explanatory messages to the console
                    and wrapper log file when the Wrapper encounters a commonly made
                    configuration mistake.  This is designed to cut down on support requests
                    by new users.  Can be disabled using the
                    <ulink url="prop-adviser.html">wrapper.adviser</ulink> property.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The bash script and the realpath utility have been deprecated since version
                    3.0.3.  They have been removed in this release.  The sh script is recommended
                    on all UNIX platforms, and the realpath utility which was used by pre-3.0.3
                    bash and sh scripts has not been used since.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the <ulink url="prop-startup-delay.html">wrapper.startup.delay</ulink>
                    property along with console and service specific variants which make it
                    possible to configure a delay between the Wrapper being launched and the
                    first JVM being launched.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Promote the <ulink url="prop-debug.html">wrapper.debug</ulink> property back
                    from being "deprecated".  It has continued to be useful and deserved
                    documentation and official status.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add <ulink url="prop-on-exit-n.html">wrapper.on_exit.&lt;n&gt;</ulink>
                    properties to control what happens when a exits based on the exit code.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modify the way calls to System.in.read() are handled so that they now block
                    rather than throwing an exception.  Currently, System.in can not be used with
                    the Wrapper because of the way I/O is passed between the Wrapper and JVM.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modified the Windows batch files to fix a problem where the path to the
                    Wrapper.exe contained more than one "/bin".  The new batch files are much
                    simpler and should be easier to customize if needed.  Bug #925308.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=925308&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425187">Bug #925308</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modified the <ulink url="prop-java-initmemory.html">wrapper.java.initmemory</ulink>
                    and <ulink url="prop-java-maxmemory.html">wrapper.java.maxmemory</ulink> properties
                    so that they now default to a value of 0 which causes the
                    <literal moreinfo="none">-Xms</literal> and <literal moreinfo="none">-Xmx</literal>
                    parameters to be omitted from the command used to launch Java.  This
                    will cause the JVM to use its own default values and also makes it possible
                    to specify the memory parameters using the
                    <ulink url="prop-java-additional-n.html">wrapper.java.additional.&lt;n&gt;</ulink>
                    properties.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a pair of <ulink url="props-envvars.html#default-definitions">environment variables</ulink>,
                    WRAPPER_FILE_SEPARATOR and WRAPPER_PATH_SEPARATOR, whose values are set to
                    either '/' and ':' or '\' and ';' on startup.  They can be used in the
                    wrapper.conf file to construct platform independent property values.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add a new <ulink url="prop-working-dir.html">wrapper.working.dir</ulink>
                    property which makes if possible to change the Wrapper and JVM's working
                    directory to a location other than the location of the Wrapper binary.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=738160&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425190">Feature Request #738160</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="3.0.5">
        <title>Version 3.0.5: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added support for SGI Irix.  Big thanks to Andreas Wendt for supplying the
                    patch.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Due to a bug in the build, the native library was not included in the 3.0.3
                    or 3.0.4 binary releases for OSX, building from source was working correctly.
                    This has been fixed and the build greatly simplified to avoid such problems
                    in the future.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=791755&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425187">Bug #791755</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Changed the default location of the pid file generated by the sh script to
                    exist in the same directory as the sh script rather than in the /var/run.
                    This can be changed by setting the PIDDIR variable in the sh script used to
                    launch the Wrapper.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added support for the <ulink url="prop-pidfile.html">wrapper.pidfile</ulink>
                    property on the Windows platform.
                </para>
                <warning>
                    <simpara>
                        (WINDOWS USERS) If you are using a wrapper.conf file that was created prior
                        to version 3.0.0 of the Wrapper, then you may have this property defined in
                        your configuration file.  You will get an error on startup if the specified
                        path does not exist.
                    </simpara>
                </warning>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added the <ulink url="prop-java-pidfile.html">wrapper.java.pidfile</ulink>
                    property which will cause the pid of the java process to be written to a
                    specified file.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Stop clearing the file creation mask when the Unix version of the Wrapper is
                    run as a daemon process.  The file creation mask will not be inherited from
                    the process which launches the Wrapper.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?func=detail&amp;atid=425187&amp;aid=788849&amp;group_id=39428">Bug #788849</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modify the sh script so it works on Linux, then deprecate the bash script.
                    This means that all Unix platforms can now use the same script to control
                    the Wrapper. Thanks to Mike Castle for the patch.  The bash script can still
                    be found in the release, but it is deprecated and will be removed in a
                    future version.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modified the sh script so it is now possible to set the nice priority in the
                    script configuration block.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Remove output to System.out in the WrapperManager.requestThreadDump() method.
                    If some JVM threads were hung while accessing the System.out object,
                    attempting to do a thread a dump would cause the calling thread to hang as
                    well.  Thanks to Thomas Hart for the patch.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Make it obvious in the log whether or not the Wrapper was started as a
                    daemon process on UNIX systems.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modify the way restarts requested from the JVM, or caused by a filter are
                    handled.  The Wrapper will no longer reset the restart count in either of
                    these cases.  If an application runs for longer than the
                    <ulink url="prop-successful-invocation-time.html">wrapper.successful_invocation_time</ulink>
                    timeout then the count will still be reset back to 0.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new <ulink url="prop-ignore-signals.html">wrapper.ignore_signals</ulink>
                    property which makes it possible to configure the Wrapper so it will ignore
                    CTRL-C, HALT and INT signals.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modify the WrapperManager.isLaunchedAsService() method on UNIX systems so it
                    now returns true if the Wrapper was launched with the
                    <ulink url="prop-daemonize.html">wrapper.daemonize</ulink> flag set.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a pair of MBean interfaces which allow the Wrapper to be controlled
                    using JMX.  See the new <ulink url="jmx.html">JMX</ulink> section in the
                    documentation for details.  Thanks to Sal Ingrilli for help with testing.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modify the Windows build so the Wrapper.exe and Wrapper.dll files can now
                    be built from <ulink url="http://ant.apache.org">Ant</ulink> if MSVC is
                    installed.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new <ulink url="prop-ping-interval.html">wrapper.ping.interval</ulink>
                    property which lets users control the frequency that the Wrapper pings the JVM.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=607768&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425190">Feature Request #607768</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    When a JVM refuses to shutdown, the Wrapper can be configured to request a
                    thread dump using the <ulink url="prop-request-thread-dump-on-failed-jvm-exit.html">wrapper.request_thread_dump_on_failed_jvm_exit</ulink>
                    property.  The Wrapper was then waiting 1 second before the process was
                    killed.  This was not always long enough, resulting in a truncated thread
                    dump.  Increased the pause to 3 seconds.  
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=633761&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425190">Feature Request #633761</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a bug where <ulink url="prop-app-parameter-n.html">wrapper.app.parameter.&lt;n&gt;</ulink>
                    and <ulink url="prop-java-additional-n.html">wrapper.java.additional.&lt;n&gt;</ulink>
                    properties declared from the Windows
                    <ulink url="props-command-line.html">command line</ulink> were not correctly
                    handling spaces in their values.
                    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=802139&amp;group_id=39428&amp;atid=425188">Support Request #802139</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="3.0.4">
        <title>Version 3.0.4: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem on UNIX systems where requesting a second thread dump any time
                    during the life of a single Wrapper process would cause the Wrapper and JVM
                    to shutdown rather than perform the thread dump.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where a, user without permission, attempting to stop an
                    application was able to delete the pid file even though they were unable
                    to stop the application itself.  This would make the scripts think that
                    the application was stopped when was actually still running.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where an application was being killed prematurely if it took
                    longer than 6 seconds to exit on its own.  The scripts now make sure that
                    an application always has enough time to shutdown cleanly.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Improve the debug output so that packet codes are now shown using a name
                    rather than a raw number.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Reduce the frequency of "Waiting to stop..." messages displayed when removing
                    an NT service that is currently running.  Decreased frequency from once per
                    second to once every five seconds.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a minor problem where the hour in the date returned by
                    WrapperInfo.getBuildTime() was not base 24.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added -t and -p command line options to the Windows version of the Wrapper
                    to sTart and stoP the Wrapper as an NT service.  This can be used in place
                    of "net start" and "net stop", which do not always work correctly when a
                    service takes a long time to start up or shutdown.  See the 
                    <ulink url="launch-win.html#exe">Launching Your Application (Win32)</ulink>
                    section for more details.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add a new method WrapperManager.stopImmediate which will cause the JVM to
                    exit immediately without calling any stop methods or shutdown hooks.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add a new class, WrapperActionServer, which makes it easy to remotely control
                    the Wrapper remotely by opening a socket and sending commands.  See the
                    <ulink url="javadocs.html">javadocs</ulink> of the class for more
                    details.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix bug #744801.  A Java GUI was not being displayed when the application was
                    run in either console mode or as a service with <ulink url="prop-ntservice-interactive.html">wrapper.ntservice.interactive</ulink>
                    enabled.  This problem was introduced in Version 3.0.0 when using 1.2.x or
                    1.3.x versions of Java.  To use interactive services with 1.2.x or 1.3.x
                    versions of java, please review the documentation for the
                    <ulink url="prop-ntservice-interactive.html">wrapper.ntservice.interactive</ulink> property.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the JVM was not receiving CTRL-C and CTRL-CLOSE events
                    when running under the Wrapper on Windows.  This was not a problem in most
                    cases as the Wrapper was taking care of the processing of the events.  But
                    the WrapperListener.controlEvent() method was not being called as documented.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Changed the way the WrapperSimpleApp and WrapperStartStopApp respond to
                    control events so that the JVM will respond and call WrapperManager.stop()
                    even when being controlled by the Wrapper.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modified the suggested behavior of the WrapperListener.controlEvent() method.
                    Users who have implemented the WrapperListener interface themselves should
                    review the <ulink url="javadocs.html">javadocs</ulink>.  The changes are not
                    required and applications will continue to function as they did before.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added support for DEC OSF1 (Alpha).  Big thanks to Andreas Wendt for
                    supplying the patch.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the sh and bash scripts were failing if the path to the
                    script contained spaces.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the JVM would sometimes hang when trying to shutdown if
                    the wrapper.key parameter was passed to the JVM while not being controlled
                    by the Wrapper.  This would happen if a user copied the command from the
                    Wrapper's debug output and attempted to run it as is without first removing
                    the wrapper.key parameter.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Implement the ability to specify an NT service's load order group in response
                    to feature request #764143.  See the javadocs for the new
                    <ulink url="prop-ntservice-load-order-group.html">wrapper.ntservice.load_order_group</ulink>
                    property for details.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Improve the error message displayed when the NT EventLog is full in response
                    to feature request #643617.  The EventLog output will now be disabled if any
                    errors are encountered while logging events.  This prevents the error from
                    repeating.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Improve the error message displayed on Windows when the configured Java
                    command can not be executed or does not exist.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the Wrapper was leaving a pipe unclosed each time the JVM
                    was restarted on all UNIX platforms.  This was causing the Wrapper to run out
                    of file handles.   Bug #767267, discovered and patched by David Wong.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the '#' character, which signifies a comment, could not
                    be included in property values.  A double hash, '##' will now resolve into a
                    '#' within the property value.  Bug #777303.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added support for FreeBSD.  Big thanks to Alphonse Bendt for supplying the
                    patch.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Make the <ulink url="prop-port.html">wrapper.port</ulink> property optional.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Changed the way environment variables are loaded from the registry on Windows
                    platforms so users will no longer get warning messages about not being able
                    to handle very large environment variables.  Prior versions could only handle
                    environment variables whose expanded value was less than 2048 characters in
                    length.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem on UNIX platforms where a shell used to start the Wrapper
                    running as a detached process would hang when the user attempted to exit
                    the shell.  Thanks to Mike Castle for this patch.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="3.0.3">
        <title>Version 3.0.3: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added support for Mac OS X.  Big thanks to Andy Barnett for supplying the
                    patch.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a segmentation fault on UNIX systems when the first console output
                    from the JVM was an empty line.  Thanks to Mike Castle for finding this.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where a 0 length malloc was being called if there were no
                    configured filters.  This was fine on most platforms but caused a crash
                    on MAC OS X.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Rework the initialization of the bash and sh scripts so that they will
                    work correctly when referenced as symbolic links.  Thanks go out to Richard
                    Emberson for the code to resolve symbolic links.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Deprecated the realpath binary in the *NIX distributions as it is no longer
                    used by the bash or sh scripts.  It is being left in for now so as not to
                    break the build scripts of other projects, but it will be removed after a
                    couple more releases.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a test to make sure that
                    <ulink url="prop-ntservice-interactive.html">wrapper.ntservice.interactive</ulink>
                    is not set to TRUE when an account is specified using
                    <ulink url="prop-ntservice-account.html">wrapper.ntservice.account</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="3.0.2">
        <title>Version 3.0.2: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modified the sh and bash scripts so that console log output is disabled by
                    default when the scripts are launched with the 'start' action.  Running with
                    the 'console' action will still send output to the console.  Logging to the
                    file is still enabled.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modified the wrapper.ping.timeout property so it also controls the ping
                    timeout within the JVM.  Before the timeout on responses to the Wrapper
                    could be controlled, but the ping timeout within the JVM was hardcoded to
                    30 seconds.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    In the last release, some work was done to avoid false timeouts caused by
                    large quantities of output.  On some heavily loaded systems, timeouts were
                    still being encountered.  Rather than reading up to 50 lines of input, the
                    code will now read for a maximum of 250ms before returning to give the main
                    event loop more cycles.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the values of environment variables set in the
                    configuration file were not correct when those values included references
                    to other environment variables.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a potential buffer overflow problem if configuration properties
                    referenced extremely large environment variables.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a potential problem where the inability to expand very large environment
                    variables would have led to an access violation when run as an NT service.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add some extra checks in the event where the native library can not be loaded
                    so that the WrapperManager can differentiate between the library missing and
                    not being readable due to permission problems.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Remove the wrapper.ntservice.process_priority from the default wrapper.conf
                    because its use can produce unexpected results if used improperly.  Please
                    see the property documentation for details.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where environment variables in the registry which had no value
                    were causing the Wrapper to crash with an access violation.  This was
                    introduced in version 3.0.0 with the feature to load environment variables
                    from the registry.  The offending registry entry was WV_GATEWAY_CFG which
                    appears to be related to Oracle.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="3.0.1">
        <title>Version 3.0.1: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem with the wrapper.disable_shutdown_hook.  Due to a typo in the
                    source, the property was being ignored.  This was broken in the 3.0.0
                    release.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem with the HP-UX release build reported by Ashish Gawarikar.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the ability to set environment variables from within the configuration
                    file or from the command line.  See the
                    <ulink url="props-envvars.html">Environment Variables</ulink> section for
                    details.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem on HP-UX and AIX machines where the stop() function in the
                    shell scripts was causing a syntax error due to a conflict with a like named
                    shell command on those platforms.  This appears to be an issue with the
                    Korn shell on all platforms.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where very heavy output from the JVM can cause the Wrapper to
                    give a false timeout.  The Wrapper now only reads 50 lines of input at a time
                    to guarantee that the Wrapper's event loop always gets cycles.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem on UNIX versions where extra line breaks would sometimes be
                    added to the logged output when there was large amounts of output being
                    sent from the JVM.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where a large number of calls to WrapperManager.log()
                    immediately before the JVM exits could lead to the Wrapper incorrectly
                    reporting that the JVM exited unexpectedly.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="3.0.0">
        <title>Version 3.0.0: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Deprecated the com.silveregg.wrapper package in favor of
                    org.tanukisoftware.wrapper.  The classes and interfaces in the silveregg
                    package will continue to function, but migration to the new package should
                    be done when possible.  See the project
                    <ulink url="history.html">history</ulink> for details.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    On Windows systems change any forward slashes in the wrapper.java.command
                    property to back slashes.  Some users had reported having problems on
                    Windows XP.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Implemented feature request #633178.  Added WrapperManager.requestThreadDump()
                    to force the current JVM to immediately perform a thread dump.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fixed bug where wrapper.logfile.maxsize was being set to 0 if the 'k' or 'm'
                    unit was omitted.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the ability to specify an account name and password when installing an
                    NT service.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add a property, wrapper.ntservice.interactive, which makes it possible to
                    control whether or not the Java process can gain access to the desktop while
                    it is running as an NT service.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add limited support for 1.2.x versions of Java.  Shutdown hooks are
                    supported until Java 1.3 so those functions will be disabled.  If the
                    application displays a GUI then Java 1.3 should be used as the GUI can not
                    currently be displayed when using Java 1.2.x.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Made it possible to use the wrapper.pidfile property on all *nix platforms.
                    Please notice that the property has been removed from the default
                    wrapper.conf file.  The property is not needed when the wrapper is launched
                    with the bash shell script.  The sh shell script will set the wrapper.pidfile
                    when the wrapper is launched.  If either of the scripts provided with the
                    Wrapper distribution are used then the wrapper.pidfile should always be
                    removed from your wrapper.conf file.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new wrapper.daemonize property which, when set, will form the wrapper
                    process to be a detached non-session group leader.  This makes it possible to
                    launch the wrapper in such a way that it will not be terminated when the user
                    launching the process logs out.  This had been a problem on Solaris systems
                    when using the sh shell.  The default sh and bash scripts both make use of
                    this in the default.  Please update your scripts for use with this version.
                    Thanks to Rajiv Subrahmanyam for the patch.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the Wrapper was incorrectly counting the number of
                    non-daemon threads in BEA's JRockit Virtual Machine.  This was causing the
                    application to shutdown when the non-daemon thread count dropped to 1.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added support for building the wrapper on AIX and HP-UX systems.  Thanks for
                    the patches involved go out to Ashish Gawarikar and William Lee.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Implement feature request #653131 to force the JVM to immediately exit when
                    the user presses CTRL-C multiple times.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a 'console' action to the bash and sh scripts to make it possible to
                    launch the Wrapper in the current shell process.  The 'start' task will launch
                    the Wrapper as a spawned daemon process.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fixed a problem where missing environment variables specified in classpath
                    or library path properties were not being handled correctly.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Implemented feature request #676599 to enable the filtering of JVM output to
                    trigger JVM restarts or Wrapper shutdowns.  See the new
                    wrapper.filter.trigger.n and wrapper.filter.action.n properties.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modify the Win32 version of the Wrapper so that Environment Variables are
                    always read from the system registry when the Wrapper is run as a service.
                    By doing this, it makes it possible to change or add the system environment
                    variables and have them take effect without having to first reboot the
                    machine.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Implemented cascading configuration files. See the
                    <ulink url="props-cascading.html">Cascading Configuration Files</ulink>
                    section for details.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Changed the default value for the wrapper.java.initmemory property to be 3Mb.
                    The default on Windows and Linux JVMs is 2Mb, but the Solaris JVM requires
                    a minimum of 3Mb.  The minimum value accepted by the Wrapper was changed
                    from 8Mb to 1Mb to make it possible to reduce the footprint of applications
                    to what is possible without using the wrapper.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Improve the parsing of configuration files so that leading and trailing white
                    space is now correctly trimmed.  It is also now possible to have comments at
                    the end of a line containing a property.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modify the way exceptions thrown by an application's main method are
                    presented to the user by the WrapperSimpleApp and WrapperStartStopApp so
                    they no longer look like a problem with Wrapper configuration.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="2.2.9">
        <title>Version 2.2.9: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new property, wrapper.restart.delay, which allows the user to control
                    the amount of time to pause between a JVM exiting and a new JVM being
                    launched.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fixed bug #611024. The Wrapper would sometimes fail to start if
                    wrapper.max_failed_invocations is set to 1.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the number of non-daemon threads was not being calculated
                    in some cases.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Implemented feature request #491443.  Environment variables referenced in the
                    wrapper.conf file will now be evaluated as the file is loaded.  The windows
                    syntax for environment variables is used on all platforms to make them
                    platform independent.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fixed a problem where the wrapper.conf was being open with both read and
                    write locks when a read lock is all that is needed.  Made the wrapper fail
                    on startup if another application held a read lock on the conf file.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modified the message displayed when the native library could not be found,
                    so that it is much more descriptive.  Hopefully it will cut down on questions
                    caused by configuration problems.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Implemented feature request #613539. Modified the wrapper.java.library.path
                    to function like the wrapper.java.classpath.n properties so that multiple
                    directories can be specified in the library path in a platform independent
                    way.  The old property is still supported, but deprecated.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix Bug #632215.  The WrapperManager.isLaunchedAsService() method was always
                    returning false, even when run as a service under Windows.  On Linux, the
                    Wrapper is always run as a console app, so this method will always return
                    false.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Improve the message thrown when user code attempts to access System.in from
                    within a JVM being controlled by the Wrapper.  System.in will not work
                    because the JVM is a spawned process.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="2.2.8">
        <title>Version 2.2.8: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fixed a compiler problem on Solaris some systems.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new property, wrapper.cpu.timeout, which allows the user to control
                    how much time without receiving any CPU the Wrapper will tolerate before
                    displaying a warning message.  The CPU timeout feature was added in 2.2.7
                    but the default timeout of 10 seconds was not configurable.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The Wrapper was only allowing 5 seconds between the JVM informing the
                    Wrapper that it was going to exit and the JVM process actually exiting.
                    This would cause the Wrapper to terminate the process prematurely in
                    cases where an application shutdown thread took longer than 5 seconds to
                    complete.  The Wrapper not allows wrapper.jvm_exit.timeout seconds for
                    the JVM process to exit on its own before being forcibly terminated.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    When there is a configuration problem or a resource is unavailable, a JVM
                    will sometimes exit abnormally very shortly after being launched.  This
                    can lead the the JVM being infinitely restarted due to a simple class
                    path misconfiguration.  To work around this, the Wrapper has always had
                    a hard limit of 5 restarts within a short period of time.  If the JVM
                    has been running for more than a few minutes, then the count was reset.
                    In this version, a new property. wrapper.max_failed_invocations was added
                    to allow the max value to be set.   The time period which the JVM must
                    now be running for the JVM launch to have been considered a success for
                    restart purposes is set using the new wrapper.successful_invocation_time
                    property.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The number of advanced properties which most users do not need has been
                    increasing as the Wrapper has been made more and more flexible.  This
                    has been causing confusion in their usage by people who play with them
                    without first reading the documentation.  To solve this, the advanced
                    properties were removed from the default configuration file.  They still
                    function.  But users must now read to the advanced configuration
                    documentation to learn about their existence.  Added quite about to the
                    descriptions of these properties to hopefully clear up any confusion
                    about their usage.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    When the JVM exits abnormally, the Wrapper will pause for a few seconds
                    before starting another JVM.  If the user pressed CTRL-C during this
                    pause, a new JVM would still be launched.  The new JVM was exiting
                    immediately but it was a waste of time.  The Wrapper now recognizes the
                    event and aborts launching the new JVM.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a page to the documentation which shows inline javadocs.  This
                    will hopefully make it easier to navigate them as part of the full
                    documentation set.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new method to the WrapperManager which enables user code to
                    log at any log level.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new Helper class WrapperStartStopApp which allows users to easily
                    integrate applications like Tomcat which use a separate class to stop
                    the application.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a samples section to the documentation.  Just includes Tomcat 4
                    for now.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="2.2.7">
        <title>Version 2.2.7: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the JVM was trying to reconnect the Wrapper as it was
                    being shutdown.  This was causing problems if the JVM was being restarted.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added support for the system being suspended to RAM or disk.  Also improved
                    wrapper performance when a system is under 100% load.  See the new example
                    output in the <ulink url="example.html">example</ulink> section. 
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the log output was not being directed to a file called
                    wrapper.log in the same directory as the Wrapper binary in the event that the
                    configured wrapper log file could not be accessed.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where the Wrapper was not shutting down the JVM correctly when
                    all non daemon threads completed.   Normally a JVM will exit when all of its
                    non daemon threads have completed so this was causing some problems.
                    (Thanks to Jung Tamas)
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added the ability to set the priority of the Wrapper and its JVM when run
                    as an NT service or console application.  The same thing can be better
                    achieved on Unix systems by using "nice" in the shell script used to launch
                    the Wrapper.  See the documentation for for details.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    JVM information was not being displayed correctly when the Wrapper native
                    library could not be loaded.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a new property to cause the wrapper to attempt to request a thread dump
                    when the JVM does not exit on request.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Improved the documentation of the WrapperSimpleApp and WrapperListener classes.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Adding a new property wrapper.shutdown.timeout to allow the user to extend the
                    length of time that an application is allowed to take shutting down.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Rework the way the shutdown process works so that System.exit will never be
                    called before the stop method in WrapperListener has had a chance to complete.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add a Restart button to the TestWrapper application.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem on Unix versions where '%' characters in Java output would
                    sometimes cause the wrapper to crash.  Somehow missed getting this into the
                    last release.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added a test to make sure that WrapperManager.stop is not called recursively.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added support for building under Windows XP.  Prebuilt installations had
                    already been working.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="2.2.6">
        <title>Version 2.2.6: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fix a problem where '%' characters in Java output would sometimes cause the
                    wrapper to crash.  (Thanks to Frode Moe)
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added support for requesting a Java thread dump without shutting down the
                    Java process.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fixed a problem on windows where the java command was looking in the windows
                    system and system32 directories for the java executable before checking the
                    path when the full path to the java executable was not specified in the
                    configuration file.  This could lead to different JVM being run from the
                    Wrapper than was run if java -version was run from the command line.  The
                    Wrapper will now attempt to resolve the full java path using the PATH
                    environment variable.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added debug output showing Java version information when the JVM first starts.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Modified c source to use /* */ style comments rather than // style comments.
                    Some people were having problems with some compilers.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="2.2.5">
        <title>Version 2.2.5: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fixed bug issue when reading configuration files from Windows on Unix.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Deprecated the wrapper.debug property in favor of loglevels.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added support for service descriptions for Win2k and XP.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added new logger functionality includes the following features: Loglevels like
                    Log4j, NT Eventlog support, UNIX syslog support and rolling log files.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added wildcard support for classpath entries in wrapper.conf.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added the ability to specify configuration properties from the command line.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Changed the way NT services are installed so that a patched version of the
                    Wrapper.exe file no longer needs to be created to reference the wrapper.conf
                    file.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="2.2.4">
        <title>Version 2.2.4: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The value of APP_NAME in the bash or sh scripts no longer needs to be the
                    same as the script.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added the ability to format and/or disable file logging and output to the
                    console.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Set mode of executables in binary release tar files so that they can be run
                    without modification after being extracted.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Fixed line feeds in release so that bat files are always CRLF, unix scripts
                    are always LF.  Other source files are always CRLF in ZIP archives and LF in
                    tar.gz archives.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Make the build fail if Wrapper.exe or Wrapper.dll do not exist for Windows
                    builds.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added an empty wrapper.log to the releases so that the TestWrapper example
                    program runs out of the box.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="2.2.3">
        <title>Version 2.2.3: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added template scripts and conf files for ease of integration with other
                    applications.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Cleaned up the build.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The WrapperSimpleApp method of launching applications was not working correctly
                    with applications whose main method did not return.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add sample scripts and wrapper.conf files in the bin and lib directories.
                    These scripts are used to start a sample application which runs out of the box.
                    See the new <ulink url="example.html">example.html</ulink> page in the
                    documentation for more details.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Get rid of the platform specific directories in the bin and lib directories.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Enable relative paths for Windows version.  In previous versions of Wrapper,
                    it was necessary to always use absolute paths because the working directory of
                    the wrapper would be then NT System32 directory when run as a service.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    On the windows version, the wrapper always sets the current working directory
                    to the location of the wrapper executable immediately after startup.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Improvements to the documentation / web page.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="2.2.2">
        <title>Version 2.2.2: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added HTML based documentation.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="2.2.1">
        <title>Version 2.2.1: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added Linux and Solaris build files.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Added Linux and Solaris documentation.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="2.2.0">
        <title>Version 2.2.0: Changes and bug fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Initial Public Release.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
</article>
